Kevin J. McIntyre

14371 Riviera Dr. Huntington Beach, CA (714) 642-9024 kevin70@yahoo.com

web: nwice.com

Infrastructure

Amazon AWS, Security Admin, System Admin

Data

MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Redis, DynamoDB

Domains

Android, Hibernate, GWT, J2EE, JQuery, JSON, NodeJS, Python, Qt, RequireJS, Rest, SecXML, Spring, Twisted, WebSocket, Web Services, XML/ XSLT

Tools

ADT, Eclipse, Git/ SVN, Jenkins, Junit, Linux, Maven, Trial, Ubuntu

Objective

Seeking opportunities in software as principle engineer, architect, and full-stack developer.

Summary

Prior to 2000 my experience was in coding all aspects of the web with ASP, Perl, Cold Fusion, and MSSQL.

Between 2000-2010, I primarily focused on open source technologies with an emphasis on Linux, apache, java/J2EE development.

Recently I have pursued my own software projects to further my learning of cloud based development authoring reactive based systems at the intersection of architecture and UI.

My development philosophy is tool based; design, fabricate, and execute; principles honed from multiple years of working with Agile methodologies.

As a member of a team and part of an organization, I've always tried to be a fun dependable co-worker, believing that successful software is a combination of clear objectives and team cohesion.



Research morningoogle.com 1/2016 –

MorninGoogle video audio mash-up experimenting with Amazon Elastic Transcoder and AWS Lambda, Github Source

Operator scewpt.com 11/2013 –

Scewpt SMTP Indisposable email via Amazon AWS, SMTP Command/Control as EC2 job creation over AWS SNS. Newsletter web crawler with test endpoints, and behavioral notification systems.

Founder athleets.com 4/2014 –

Athleets tweet stream contextualization powered by Twisted, QT, Autobahn, DynamoDB, S3, Cloudfront. See Junkeet, D1tweets

Personal nwice.com 11/2012 –

Multiple projects including Android App, test-bed with HTML5 version written in JQuery, RequireJS, Node.js with runtime components rendering in 2d canvas. See blackjack4all.com, Automated War

Professional Experience

Consultant Nike 2/2016 –

Full-stack engineer on Nike Present IOS application. Primary responsibility implementing new features on web-application backend running on Tomcat, Spark, MongoDB with Spock/Groovy tests.

Consultant *MapJam.com* 10/2015 – 1/2016

Full-stack engineer responsible for several initiatives including migrating from MongoDB to Postges modeled with SequelizeJS. Additionally responsible for AWS infrastructure deployment with auto-scaling groups with Ansible, static map rendering via WebKit, Qt and PyQT.

Consultant Intuit 10/2014 – 9/2015

Javascript developer on ecommerce/sign-up portion of Quickbooks. Part of team developing a new purchase flow experience, using AngularJS, Karma, and RequireJS, featuring decoupled internationalization and localization modules to deliver across all Intuit.com domains.

Consultant *Esri* 4/2013 – 7/2013

Architect on ecommerce portion of ArcGIS for Developers. Multi-tiered maven project, bridging Salesforce API with Spring and Java Jersey, serving rest-based json to javascript clients. Included components: Memcached, Amazon ElastiCache, TestNG, and Java Jackson. Working environment emphasis was on test driven development.

Senior Developer

Green Charge Networks

8/2011 - 4/2013

Key contributor on products Greenstation, and GridSynergy for Green Charge Networks. Lead development on prototype of event-driven embedded system controller using Twisted. Device provided mitigation and curtailment of energy usage through control of inverter battery, photovoltaic, and electric vehicle charging systems. Monitoring was provided via reporting to Redis, and was controlled via GridSynergy network operations center, securely hosted in Amazon Web Services. Developed real-time charting system using Google Visualization, a tool used extensively during testing, operations, and new business development. Managed the release of multiple iterations of the software across the installation sites at 7-11, and Avis car rental. Contributor to corporate IP, authoring several patents on grid-tied battery control systems. Contributing developer on network operation J2EE software, using Maven, Tomcat, Hibernate, Spring, and Google Web Toolkit.

Java Architect Freelancers Union 4/2008 – 2/2011

Lead developer on a medical portal for the Freelancers Union. Implemented project using Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Xdoclet, MantisBT targeting Linux/CentOS running Apache, Jboss 4.2.3, and Oracle 11g. Application featured services that serialized third-party EDI file into a data warehouse. Web application featured SSO modules to view patient claims information on third-party websites written in OpenSAML and SAML 2.0. Developed administrative web application for call center representatives to view enrollment changes, and manage portal users. Also, performed key roles through two billing/enrollment vendor transitions, contributing as quality assurance tester, business liaison, and lead developer spanning the lifecycle of the projects.

Engineered enterprise Swing application for an industry leading health club chain. Application featured JNLP WebStart client brokering calls via EJB SessionBeans to a server, running Jboss 4.0.5 and MSSQL 2005. Responsible for all facets of development. Established a test environment, installed tracking software to manage bugs and feature requests. Coded to J2EE standards, improving security using IP and MAC addressing, resolving cross-country latency issues while implementing or fixing bugs/features. Acted as DBA: modified schema to implement new features, wrote stored procedures using cursors and common table expressions. Additional duties included Cold Fusion development on the corporate sales website, and ASP.net development on the public facing website.

Software Developer

lamplify.com

7/2005 - 8/2006

Lead software development at lamplify.com. Server administrator for linux servers running Apache2 (mod_php & OSCommerce), Jboss, Ruby, and MySQL. Project lead for embedded flash player initiative, and lead developer of associated reporting tool, providing key metrics such as registrations, purchases, and downloads. Lead development on co-branded storefronts (HarperCollins) written using Eclipse, Maven, and Xdoclet. Coded servlets, listeners, and taglibs, utilizing a custom templating engine. Developed deployment tool enabling designers and content managers to easily tweak, test and deploy each storefront. Additional duties included PHP scripting on fulfillment system, and development of media tools website.

Software Consultant Blueprint 1/2004 – 2/2005

Consultant to Blueprint, a pharmaceutical branding company. Lead developer of application connecting doctors and patients. Established a data center, and lead development through multiple life-cycles, working with graphic designers and a junior developer. Written with Xdoclet to be application server and database agnostic, and ran seamlessly on Jboss/MySQL and WebLogic/Oracle infrastructure. Additional duties included work on client websites such as Rockport, and DFKing.

Consultant

NYC Department of Probation

12/2002 - 1/2004

Consultant to NYC Department of Probation, lead developer on automated probationer check-in system, managing 4 junior developers. Application utilized touch-screen monitor, and active-x controllers for web-cameras, palm-scanners, and printing. Developed using with Eclipse, Ant, and Xdoclet using remote EJB CMP Beans connecting to Informix database, JMS topics for probationer alerts, unit testing with JUnit, and MVC architecture with Struts form handling.

Lead Developer Volatile Media 3/1999 – 8/2000

Lead developer for Volatile Media, owner of multimedia start-up EZCD.com. Responsible for production infrastructure of a custom CD burning service, featuring samples of music as well as game demos for creating a custom mixed media CD. Developed websites using MSSQL, Cold Fusion, and java services supporting back-end manufacturing. Developed mailing-list, calendar, and content management tools allowing artists to promote their music. Responsible for interviewing/hiring junior developers and managed aspects of a small office including networking, Exchange server, and ISP relationships.

Education